Hello! In this video you will learn how it was
possible to steal all your private and unlisted
videos from YouTube by spoofing a YouTube TV
and exploiting a CSRF vulnerability. Unlike the
previous write-up I covered on my channel
about the topic, this bug allows to steal
the whole video with sound, with original
quality and without knowing the video ID.
It was identified by a hunter who knows everything
about YouTube - David Schütz. Link to his blog
post is in the description. Enjoy! On YouTube,
you can pair your phone or your browser with the
TV to control it remotely. To do this you can
be signed to a different account and you can be
on a different network than the TV. Interestingly,
on the TV you can also play your private videos.
And I'm not gonna lie, a few times I was wondering
how does this work but I thought that in order to
test this, I would need to somehow attach to my
TV so i didn't do that. But the truth is that
YouTube TV app just uses a WebView. WebView allows
the application to embed a website and YouTube TV
app just embeds youtube.com/tv URL this way.
While visiting this address from your browser,
you can just change the user-agent and you will
be served the TV version of the application.
Then, you can pair a TV with the browser or the
phone. The process looks like this: First, the TV
requests a screen_id from generate_screen_id
endpoint. Then, using this screen_id,
the TV requests a lounge_token. This token
will be very important later in the exploit.
Next, the TV sends a request to get_pairing_code
endpoint with the lounge_token and in the response
there's a 9 digit PIN code. This PIN code is
presented on the screen. Then, the user fills in
this PIN code in the browser. The browser makes a
request to get_screen endpoint with this PIN code.
if the PIN code is valid, the response contains
a lounge_token for the user. It's the same token
as in step 3 and it allows the user to control
the TV. From now on, the TV periodically sends
requests to the /bind endpoint to see if
there are any new commands from the user.
When the user clicks on "watch on TV" button, the
browser makes a POST request to the /bind endpoint
with the ID of the video and the lounge_token.
Then, the lounge API responds to the TV
with ID of that video which is then played for the
user. So we can just change the ID of the video to
a private, one you might think... but it's not
that easy because when the video is private,
the response from the lounge API contains an
additional parameter: ctt. It's a token that
allows the TV to access the private video. The
hunter did not identify any bugs on this side
of the process, at least in this write-up.
But there was a problem on the client-side
of the flow. Namely, the POST request to the
/bind endpoint had no CSRF protection at all.
So let's change the attitude here. Instead of
attacking the YouTube server to give us access
to private videos of other users, we will attack
the user and play his private video on our TV.
What do I mean by our TV? Well, YouTube TV
is just a website. To play the video as a TV
you don't need any hardware token or anything.
You just need to make a few API calls to be
able to communicate with YouTube API. High-level
overview of the attack looks like this:
First, we create a malicious TV or rather just
a script that communicates with YouTube API
like a TV. Then, we pair the victim's
browser with our TV from step 1.
Next, using the CSRF attack, we make the
victim play their private videos on our TV,
thus bypassing the access control. Let's take a
closer look at pairing the victim with our TV.
It's a five-step process and the user must
fill in the PIN code first. It would be hard
to perform this using just a CSRF. But in our
case, we don't need it. Actually, the process
is created like this so that the normal user only
needs to rewrite nine digits into their browser.
Then, the browser exchanges
the PIN for a lounge_token.
Obviously, it would be insane to make the user
rewrite the whole lounge_token but in our case,
when we are executing a CSRF attack, the victim
will be on our website anyway. So we can skip this
part with PIN codes and just put the lounge_token
on the CSRF proof of concept website for the
victim to use. With this, we have the pairing
process taken care of. How about the video ID?
At the beginning, I told you that this
attack doesn't require leaking the video ID.
What do we then send to the /bind
endpoint in context of the victim?
Instead of video ID, we can send ID of the
playlist. When you create a new playlist,
it gets an identifier that is not predictable.
However, you have a few playlists that YouTube
creates for you by default: watch later
playlist with identifier WL, liked videos with
identifier LL, but the most useful for us is
Uploads playlist with all your videos, including
private ones. You can create the playlist ID based
on the channel ID of the victim. For example, this
is my channel ID. You can see it by just visiting
my channel, it's not secret. And this is the ID
of my Uploads playlist. They differ only on the
second character: instead of C there is U letter.
If you open that playlist, you can only see my
public and unlisted videos but I will also see
the private ones there. So in our exploit, instead
of requesting a video ID, we request a list
ID with the uploads playlist ID. You can hardcode
it onto the web page when targeting a victim.
Then, this request will be sent from our website
in the context of the victim. The authentication
cookie will be attached. How does this happen
with SameSite cookie attribute? Well, Google
doesn't seem to particularly like this security
mechanism and sets the SameSite value to None
for most cookies which makes the CSRF possible.
After the request is sent to the lounge API,
our TV makes a request to the /bind endpoint
which responds with the video ID for the first
video from the Uploads playlist and a ctt token
that allows watching a video if it was private.
David created a proof of concept script that does
this whole exfiltration phase for you and reads
all victim's private and unlisted videos. You
can read the script yourself if you want. The
link is in the description. It also contains all
the steps required to communicate with YouTube
API like a TV. He was rewarded $6,000 for
that report. The fix was simple - now the
/bind endpoint requires a Bearer Authentication
header, making the CSRF impossible. That's it
for this video. If you've made it that
far, feed the YouTube algorithm with a
like so that it recommends the video to other
hackers that can learn something from it. Also,
sign up for my newsletter. Apart from getting more
tips and tutorials from me, you can also get there
the best deals for any products that I create.
But for now, thank you for watching and goodbye!